<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sloth Facts</string>
    <string name="image">Image</string>
    <string-array name="sloth_facts">
        <item>Captive sloths sleep about 15 to 18 hours a day.</item>
        <item>A sloth\'s stomach can make up to two thirds of its body weight.</item>
        <item>The three-toed sloth\'s scientific name, Bradypus, is Greek for \"slow feet.\"</item>
        <item>The sloth is the world\'s slowest animal.</item>
        <item>Sloths are so slow that algae grows on their fur.</item>
        <item>A two-toed sloth can rotate its head nearly 90 degrees.</item>
        <item>Sloths always look as if they\'re smiling due to the shape of their mouth.</item>
        <item>Sloth claws are around 3 to 4 inches long.</item>
        <item>Sloths poop once a week.</item>
        <item>Ancient sloths grew to be as large as modern day elephants.</item>
        <item>Ancient sloths roamed North America and became extinct around 10,000 years ago.</item>
        <item>Sloths enjoy sleeping in the forks of trees.</item>
        <item>Sloths live solo lives. The closest a sloth gets to socializing, aside from mating, is sleeping in the same tree with another sloth.</item>
        <item>When a female sloth wants to mate, she will yell her \"mating scream\" to alert the males around her.</item>
        <item>Males fight to mate by hanging from tree branches with their feet and pawing at each other with their front claws.</item>
        <item>Sloths have a 4 part stomach, like cows.</item>
        <item>It can take up to a month for a sloth to digest one meal.</item>
        <item>Some species of sloths are threatened due to deforestation in Central and South America.</item>
        <item>Two-toed sloths are mostly nocturnal, sleeping during the day.</item>
        <item>There are 6 species of sloths, divided into 2 main families: two-toed sloths and three-toed sloths.</item>
        <item>Sloths have difficulty walking on the ground due to their long claws.</item>
        <item>Sloths sometimes eat the algae off of their own fur as a snack.</item>
        <item>The algae that grows on sloths gives them a natural camouflage.</item>
        <item>Sloths specialize in eating leaves, tender shoots, and buds.</item>
        <item>Sloths can only manage to cover about 6&#8211;8 feet (1.8&#8211;2.4 meters) a minute.</item>
        <item>Humans walk around 39 times faster than an average sloth\'s movement.</item>
        <item>Sloths are surprisingly good swimmers.</item>
        <item>When sloths swim, they use a lazy, doggy-paddle stroke to move through the water.</item>
        <item>Sloths cannot shiver.</item>
        <item>Baby sloths stay by their mother\'s side for up to 4 years.</item>
        <item>The leaves of a sloth\'s diet are difficult to digest.</item>
        <item>Sloths\' bodies are only 25% muscle.</item>
        <item>If a sloth is too cold, it becomes unable to digest its food.</item>
        <item>A sloth only has its claws for defense against predators.</item>
        <item>Hibiscus flowers are considered \"sloth chocolate.\"</item>
        <item>Sloths can retain their grip on tree branches after their death.</item>
        <item>Wild sloths sleep for only around 9 and a half hours a day.</item>
        <item>\"Perezoso\" is \"sloth\" in spanish.</item>
        <item>An entire ecosystem can live on a single sloth.</item>
        <item>A three-toed sloth can rotate its head up to 270 degrees in either direction.</item>
        <item>The actress Kristen Bell is a big fan of sloths.</item>
        <item>A single sloth may be home to moths, beetles, cockroaches, fungi, and algae.</item>
        <item>There is a special kind of moth that has evolved to live in sloth fur.</item>
        <item>Sloths\' primary predators are eagles, snakes, and jaguars.</item>
        <item>Captive sloths can live up to 40 years.</item>
        <item>Sloths are closely related to armadillos and anteaters.</item>
        <item>Sloths are around 2&#8211;2.5 feet long.</item>
        <item>Sloths weigh from 8 to 17 pounds, depending on the species.</item>
        <item>In ancient times, there were several species of aquatic sloths, which are now extinct.</item>
        <item>Two-toed sloths have been known to eat insects, small reptiles, and even birds.</item>
        <item>Sloths can move up to 10 ft a minute in the trees.</item>
        <item>Sloths can extend their tongues 10 to 12 inches out of their mouths.</item>
        <item>Baby sloth cries sound like human babies.</item>
        <item>When looking for mates, female sloths emit a bloodcurdling scream that can be heard for 700 meters.</item>
        <item>Sloths move 3 times faster in water than on land.</item>
        <item>The pygmy three-toed sloth is critically endangered, with only around 70 individuals remaining.</item>
        <item>Wild sloths can live up to 20 years.</item>
        <item>Sloths can hold their breath underwater for up to 40 minutes.</item>
        <item>Sloths do not sweat.</item>
        <item>Sloth fur grows away from the extremities due to their time spend hanging upside down.</item>
        <item>Sloths can lose up to a third of their body weight by going to the bathroom.</item>
        <item>The Cecropia leaves of a sloth\'s diet are highly toxic.</item>
        <item>The orientation of their fur helps the rain water drip off their body.</item>
        <item>Sloth stomachs house a mix of bacteria to help break down the tough leaves of their diet.</item>
        <item>Sloths have the slowest digestion time of any mammal.</item>
        <item>Sloths rely on the sun to regulate their body temperate.</item>
        <item>Sloths maintain low body temperatures of 24 to 33 degrees.</item>
        <item>Sloths are often sold as pets on the black market to tourists, with their claws removed.</item>
        <item>Habitat loss has driven sloths into the city, where they become susceptible to being hit by cars, caught in electrical lines, or poached.</item>
        <item>Sloth fur is very thick, coarse, and wiry.</item>
        <item>When threatened, sloths can bite and produce high-pitched sounds to defend themselves.</item>
        <item>Sloths have small molars that they use to chew up their leaves.</item>
        <item>Sloths sometimes nest in the crowns of palm trees and camouflage as coconuts.</item>
        <item>Female sloths give birth to one baby at a time.</item>
        <item>Contrary to popular belief, sloths rarely die from a fall.</item>
        <item>Sloths have half as much muscle tissue as other animals of similar weight.</item>
        <item>Sloths have a very short and stubby tail.</item>
        <item>Sloth fur aids in their ability to move swiftly through water.</item>
        <item>In some areas, sloths have been estimated to comprise 70% of the biomass of arboreal mammals.</item>
        <item>Three-toed sloths sleep during the night, contrary to their two-toed counterparts.</item>
        <item>Sloths only move when necessary.</item>
        <item>Sloths spend the bulk of their time feeding on a single tree\'s leaves.</item>
        <item>Several zoos have accidentally purchased sloths of the wrong sex.</item>
        <item>There is a sloth sanctuary in Costa Rica that cares for wounded and abandoned sloths.</item>
        <item>Sloths spend most of their day sleeping and eating.</item>
        <item>Sloths have been known to drop from trees straight into water to take a swim.</item>
        <item>If a sloth feels threatened, they can go up to 4 meters a minute, however, this expends their energy quickly.</item>
        <item>Sloths have only 10 upper teeth and 8 lower teeth.</item>
        <item>When frightened, a sloth\'s fur \"puffs out,\" almost doubling its size.</item>
        <item>An external coat of long coarse hair and dense smooth undercoat provides good insulation.</item>
        <item>Sloths have 18 teeth.</item>
        <item>Sloths have no enamel coating on their teeth.</item>
        <item>Sloth teeth grows throughout its lifetime.</item>
        <item>Sloths have small ears that are embedded in their fur close to their head.</item>
        <item>Sloth are very hard of hearing.</item>
        <item>Sloth\'s eyes are very mobile, and can be partly retracted into their skull when their eyelids are closed.</item>
        <item>There is evidence that shows that sloths have adaptation to night vision.</item>
        <item>Sloths often blink frequently and slowly, one eye at a time.</item>
        <item>Sloths have difficulty maintaining their body temperature on rainy days.</item>
        <item>Sloths give birth upside down.</item>
        <item>Sloths have an excellent sense of smell.</item>
        <item>Sloth infants separated from their mothers will let out a loud bleat lasting 30&#8211;90 seconds.</item>
        <item>Sloths can hiss to defend themselves.</item>
        <item>Sloths\' ears are particularly sensitive to low frequencies.</item>
        <item>Sloth mouths house a large thick tongue, densely covered with sharp, backward-directed spines.</item>
        <item>Sloths seldom drink, as moisture is obtained from plant matter and dew on the leaves they eat.</item>
        <item>Sloth\'s milk is more nutritious than cow\'s milk.</item>
        <item>Sloths pee and poop simultaneously.</item>
        <item>Goat\'s milk is the only other milk that infant sloths can tolerate.</item>
        <item>Sloth\'s milk contains many antibodies.</item>
        <item>Sloths are born with their eyes open and claws fully formed.</item>
        <item>Sloths are poached by hunters for their pelts, and sometimes their meat.</item>
        <item>Sloths face habitat loss due to ranching, agriculture, urban expansion, and logging.</item>
        <item>On average, sloths travel 41 yards per day; less than half the length of a football field.</item>
        <item>Males are distinguishable from females as they usually have a bright yellow or orange patch located between their shoulders.</item>
        <item>The giant ground sloth was likely hunted to extinction by man following the last Ice Age.</item>
        <item>Sloths have a 120&#8211;150 day gestation period.</item>
        <item>A sloth spends approximately 85% of its life hanging upside down.</item>
        <item>All of its internal organs, including the heart, liver, spleen, and stomach, are arranged in such a way for a sloth to lead a life upside down.</item>
        <item>Sloths take 6 seconds to have sex.</item>
        <item>It takes a sloth 6 hours to go down its tree and go to the bathroom, and back up.</item>
        <item>A baby sloth begins eating leaves at 2 months old.</item>
        <item>Baby sloths are born fully furred.</item>
        <item>Cold spells can be dangerous for sloth populations as they must move about to eat, but are not warm enough to move.</item>
        <item>The sloth has the slowest metabolism of any mammal on Earth.</item>
        <item>Both two-toed and three-toed sloths have three toes on their hind limbs.</item>
        <item>Sloths become more inactive during the rainy season.</item>
        <item>Orphaned baby sloths are given stuffed animals for them to hold onto.</item>
        <item>Orphaned baby sloths are susceptible to illness as goat\'s milk lacks the antibodies of their mother\'s milk.</item>
        <item>Sloths have no incisors or canines.</item>
        <item>The only place sloths deposit fat is on the pads of their feet.</item>
        <item>Sloths cannot fart.</item>
        <item>Sloths have one baby at a time.</item>
        <item>Twin sloths are incredibly rare, and when they do happen, the mother is unable to care for them both.</item>
        <item>To move on ground, sloths dig into the earth with their front claws and pull themselves along, dragging their bellies across the forest floor.</item>
        <item>The three-toed sloth emits a long, high-pitched call that echoes through the forests as "ahh-eeee."</item>
        </string-array>
</resources>